laptoping.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy, Cookies, and Disclaimer – Laptoping

## Privacy Policy and Cookie Use

We are committed to safeguard your privacy on our website (Laptoping). 

All personal information that you entrust to Laptoping by submitting comments on our articles, contacting us via contact forms, or any other action will be treated confidentially and will not be sold to third parties. 

Laptoping uses cookies and other web technologies to collect visitors’ data (such as their IP addresses, Internet service provider names, browser types, visit lengths, and similar) in order to administer the website better. 

Cookies are small text files sent to your web browser by a website you visit. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows Laptoping or a third-party to recognize you and make your next visit easier and the Laptoping more useful to you. The collected data is not linked to personally identifiable information. 

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

Also, visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

Pages on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website. These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Some of our advertisers use cookies and other web technologies on Laptoping to collect personally non-identifiable visitors’ data. They primarily use collected information in order to deliver better ads. Laptoping has no access to these cookies, but assumes they don’t pose any threat to its visitors. 

Also, some other 3rd parties like social media networks may know you visited this website, if you use their services. We have no control over them.

Visitors can disable or selectively turn off cookies delivered via Laptoping by blocking them in web browser or security software settings.

By continuing to browse the website, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

## Disclaimer

Laptoping website is provided as a service to the public.

Laptoping is not responsible for, and expressly disclaims all liability for, damages of any kind arising out of use, reference to, or reliance on any information contained within the site. While the information contained within the site is periodically updated, no guarantee is given that the information provided in this Web site is correct, complete, and up-to-date.

Laptoping contains links to other websites and is not responsible for content and privacy practices of these websites.

Laptoping is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

This website is also a participant in other affiliate and advertising programs.

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy and disclaimer, please [contact us](https://laptoping.com/contact-us/).
